(飛段)逃がさねえってか？ ケッ！
So you won't let me get away, huh?
フン。 この影技
５分くらいが限界なんだろ。
This shadow technique only lasts
about five minutes, right?
そして ２人きり…。
And it's just the two of us...
そりゃ
こっちも好都合なんだよ バカが！
That works out well for me, too.
You idiot!
(飛段)ハッ！
(シカマル)うわっ！
ヘッ ヘヘヘッ…。
うおっ！
(角都)オレのストックしておける
心臓は 己のを含め ５つ。
I can stock five hearts including my own.
カカシ お前に減らされたぶんは
お前の心臓をいただく。
Kakashi... I will take your heart to
replace the one you took from me!
ヘヘヘヘッ…。
条件は整った。
Everything's ready...
(いの)別々だった２体が融合した。
The two separate bodies merged.
《カカシ : 融合したのは
火遁と風遁の面か…》
So the Fire Style...
and Wind Style masks merged, huh?
カカシ お前に減らされたぶんは
お前の心臓をいただく。
Kakashi... I will take your heart to
replace the one you took from me!
《カカシ : そっちか！》
That one, huh?!
《こうも開けた場所じゃ
狙い打ちか…》
He's trying to force me
into an open area
where he can shoot me down, huh?
それで隠れたつもりか？
Is that your idea of hiding?
(２人)先生！
- Sensei!
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
explain to me this happiness
anata ga saikin taiken shita
that you just got to experience?
shiawase wa ittai nan desu ka
or maybe you're so blessed
megumare sugite ite
that you can't even remember it
omoidasenai kamo
that you stand here now
ima koko ni iru koto
that you still live and breathe
iki wo shite iru koto
I realised that they all were miracles
tada soredake no koto ga
just by themselves
kiseki da to kidzuku
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
you know the closer you get to something
the tougher it is to see it
and i'll never take it for granted
it's fine to say you'll never give up
oi tsudzukete kita yume
and to keep chasing your dreams
akiramezu ni susumeyo nante
but the more time you spend talking big
kirei goto wo ieru hodo
the less you get done
nanimo dekicha inai kedo
I will press that handful of courage against my heart
hito nigiri no yuuki wo mune ni
and with its help survive another day
ashita wo ikinuku tame ni
and i'll never take it for granted
let's go
Shikamaru's Genius
(チョウジ)あっ…。
フーッ。
(角都)今度はうまく隠れたな カカシ。
You did a good job of
hiding this time, Kakashi.
しかし また我々の前に
姿を現す勇気があるかな？
But do you have the courage to
show yourself before us again?
ん？
《またか！》
Not again!
水遁 水陣壁！
Water Style: Water Wall!
《風の性質変化が加わった火じゃ
水遁だけでは消せないか…》
Fire with the wind Change
in Chakra Nature added to it...
can't be put out just
with Water Style, huh?
《やはり 本体に
接近戦を挑まないと…》
Looks like I'll have to confront him
at close range, after all.
ぐわっ！
あっ！
カカシ先生！
Kakashi-sensei!
(角都)オレの動きまで
気が回らなかったようだな。
It appears you didn't get around
to watching out for my movements.
もらうぞ！ お前の心臓。
Your heart... is mine.
死ね！
(シカマル)うっ！
Die!
どうだ？
病みつきになる痛みだろ。
How about that...?
It's addicting pain, isn't it?
ゴホッ…。
((アスマ : 頼んだぞ シカマル…))
I'm counting on you... Shikamaru...
ケッ くだらねえ。
How worthless...
これじゃ ジャシン様もがっかりだぜ。
Lord Jashin must be disappointed...
さて 角都のほうも
さすがにもう終わってんだろ。
Now...
Kakazu must be about finished
by now, too...
(角都)うっ…。
なにを…！
Wh-What did you do?
なんとか… 間に合ったようだな。
It seems...
he made it just in time...
うっ… ま… まさか…。
I-Impossible!
ふぅ…。
行くか。
Time to go...
《浅いか！》
Not deep enough?!
(飛段)テメエ…！
You bastard...
なんで 生きてる!?
Why are you alive?!
(飛段)テメエ… なんで 生きてる!?
You bastard...
Why are you alive?
オレは ただ…
やられたフリをしていただけだ。
I just pretended...
that I was dead.
その武器に付着している血は
オレのじゃない。
The blood on that weapon... isn't mine.
あ…？
アンタの相方の血だ。
It's your partner's blood.
ぐぅ… ま… まさか…。
I-Impossible...
あぁ その まさかだ。
Yes, it is possible.
お前の相方の儀式に
お前自身の血を利用したのさ。
Your own blood was used
for your partner's ritual.
((シカマル : じゃあ カカシ先生 これ。
So, Kakashi-sensei, here...
(隙を見て 使ってください。
渡しておきます))
Please use it when there is a chance.
I'll let you keep it.
(カカシ)シカマルには
ヤツが血を利用する能力があると➡
Shikamaru knew his opponent's ability
utilized blood, after all.
わかっていたからな。 あらかじめ
血液用カプセルを用意してたんだよ。
He'd prepared capsules
of blood in advance.
(飛段)どういうことだ!?
誰でもいい。
What does that mean?
チャンスがあれば
角都ってヤツの血を抜き取る。
Anyone would've been fine...
If given an opportunity,
we needed to get your partner's blood.
このカプセルの中にな。
In this capsule, you see...
バカな…。
It can't be...
When did you have the chance?!
いつ そんな隙が…。
オレの雷切で 穴をあけたとき。
When I put a hole inside you
with my Lightning Blade...
(カカシ)一緒に
お前の血を いただいたのさ。
I took your blood at the same time.
((アイツは オレ一人で捕まえる。
I'll capture him by myself.
(そして… あの役は オレがやる))
And...
And I'll fulfill that role...
(シカマル)そして それを
受け取ったオレが アンタを ハメる役。
So I took it... and my role was to trap you.
((飛段 : おい！
どこへ行こうってんだ！
Hey, where are we going?
角都とオレを引き離す気か!?
Are you trying to separate me
from Kakuzu?!
フッ…。
テメエ！
Bastard...!
(角都)誰も ついていかなくて
いいのか？
Shouldn't someone go with him?
飛段を見くびりすぎだ。
You're really underestimating Hidan.
あの シカマルとかいう若造…
高値の賞金首になっただろうに。
And here, that kid called Shikamaru
or whatever...
would've become a bounty
of high value someday.
今日で… 死ぬぞ。
Today... he dies.
(ひゃっは～！ うらぁ！))
それが こっちの作戦だったのさ。
Heh. That was... our strategy.
や… 野郎…！
Bastard...!
バカな…。 あの若造… そこまで…！
No way...
That kid... He planned that far ahead...
そういうことだ。 もっと慎重に
対処すべきだったな。
That's about the size of it.
You should've handled him
more carefully...
お前らこそ
シカマルを見くびりすぎだ。
You guys really underestimated him.
アスマが命と引きかえに残した情報を
アイツが ムダにするわけがない。
There's no way he would
let the information
that cost Asuma his own life
go to waste.
なんのためらいもなく 人の命を
奪ってきた お前たちには➡
You guys who take peoples' lives
without hesitation
アイツの気持は
わからないだろうな。
could probably never understand
how he feels.
(チョウジ)カカシ先生！
(いの)大丈夫ですか？
Kakashi-sensei!
ま なんとかな。
Are you okay?
Well... somehow I guess.
《あの短時間で
ここまで侵蝕してるなんて…。
I can't believe they invaded
his body this much
シカマルが もう少し遅れていたら…》
in such a short period of time.
If Shikamaru had taken any longer...
ゆっくり！
血管を傷つけないように。
Slowly! Make sure not to damage
the vessels.
すぐに 医療忍術で手当てします！
I'll treat you immediately
with my Medical Ninjutsu.
手当ては 後だ！
The treatment can wait!
くるぞ！
What?!
Here they come!
倍化の術！
Expansion Jutsu!
超張り手！
Super Slap!
はぁ～!!
やるぅ いいぞ チョウジ！
Nice! Good one, Choji!
ヘヘヘ！
うん？
チョウジ！
Choji!
(カカシ)なに!?
What?!
しまった！
え!?
Crap!
What?!
生き返った…。
あの雷遁のバケモノの心臓を
取り込んだんだ。
He came back to life?
He absorbed the Lightning Style
monster's heart.
むぅ!!
なに あれ!?
What's that...?
本体も まんま バケモノだな。
His main body's a monster, too.
オレの心臓を ２つも…。
Two of my hearts... gone.
久方ぶりだぞ それは。
It's been a long time...
since that happened...
(飛段)ヘッヘッヘ…。
さほど 利口でないオレにだって
わかるぜ。
Even I can tell,
and I'm not all that bright...
いったい 何度目だって話だよ…。
It's been so many times already.
こう何度も
同じ術にかかってりゃ➡
Any idiot could figure out your Jutsu
after seeing it so many times.
バカでも その特徴がわかるぜ。
(シカマル)なんだと!?
What did you say?
術に
さっきまでの力がないようだな。
It seems your Jutsu isn't as strong
as it was before.
５分も いらなかったな。
I didn't even need five minutes...
動けるぜ。
I can move!
お前… 縛るたびに➡
The endurance of your Jutsu power
and its effect
だんだん術の強さと
効果の持続時間が➡
gradually decreases each time
you use it.
お粗末になってきてるぜ。
フン！
(飛段)つまるところ➡
Basically, the longer you use it,
the weaker it gets.
この影術は 使えば使うほど➡
それに比例して
術全体の効力が 低下する。
うぅ…。
(飛段)お前 そろそろ➡
Aren't you just about out of Chakra? Huh?!
チャクラの限界なんじゃないのか？
えぇ？ おい！
うぅ…。
ハハハハ！
ワーッハハハ!!
今度は 逃がさん。
You won't get away... this time.
来るぞ！
(２人)はい！
Here he comes!
- Right!
《うっ 速い！》
キャー！
He's fast!
クソッ！
《動けない…》
Damn it!
I can't move...!
(角都)はたけ カカシ。
Kakashi Hatake...
お前で 失った心臓の
補充をする気だったが➡
I was going to replace the hearts
I lost with yours...
気が変わった…。
But I've changed my mind...
(角都)心臓の補充など
別に いつでもできるからな。
I can get more hearts
anytime I want, after all...
あ！
死ね！
Die!
(ナルト)風遁 螺旋丸！
Wind Style: Rasengan!
(ヤマト)水遁 破奔流！
Water Style: Ripping Torrent!
(ナルト/ヤマト)颶風水渦の術！
Hurricane Vortex Jutsu!
遅くなって すまねえってばよ。
Sorry... we're late.
ふぅ…。
いいタイミングだ。
Perfect timing...
what made me think
kondo wa itsu aeru ka nante
how can you say that with a straight face
sonna kao shite yoku ieru tte
when you asked we will meet again
omotteta yo nande darou
any time you talk to much I don't get it
any time shaberisugi no k y
for a moment I see your bluff and I cry
chirari miseru tsuyogari na i cry
do my tears even work on you?
namida no kouka wa dore kurai
I keep saying "I want to be loved"
watashi nari ni aisaretai
in my own special way but you still don't get the hint
afureru no ni kimi ga mienai
this nagging feeling I feel
nidoto kimi ni aenai
that I'll never see you again...
sonna ki ga suru nda
I wish I could tell you but I can't find the words
tsutaetai no ni umai kotoba miataranai
maybe I'd rather listen to you lie
watashi tabun uso demo ii no ni
I can't even say "don't leave me"
ikanaide mo ienai yo
when you let go of my hand
nigitteta te ga hanaretara
will you forget someday?
kimi wa itsuka wasurechau no
about me
watashi no koto
I wish I could tell you but I can't find the words
tsutaetai no ni umai kotoba miataranai watashi tabun
(ヤマト)
いびきが うるさくて眠れない…。
イテッ!!
待って…。
maybe I'd rather listen to you lie 'cause I can't even say "don't leave me"
uso demo ii no ni ikanaide mo ienai yo
なんという寝相の悪さだ…。
これじゃあ おちおち
寝てられない！
あ!!
ま… 待て ナルト 目を覚ませ！
それは いくらなんでも…！
Next Episode
Do you know what those words mean?
(ヤマト)うわ～!!
It means if you curse someone
and attempt to kill them,
you will also be killed in retribution,
so two burial pits are necessary.
グッド モーニング！ …って あれ？
You cursed and killed my teacher.
ヤマト隊長 どうしたんだ？
Don't think you guys can
just romp about carefree...
あぁ… ちょっとね…。
うわ～!!
That's your burial pit.
《ヤマト : しかし この人
あの状況で よく…》
Next time:
"When You Curse Someone,
You Dig Your Own Grave"
When You Curse Someone
You Dig Your Own Grave
う～ん…。
(ヤマト)あ!!
ん？ どうしたんだ？
カカシ先輩… ずるいっすよ…。
— His snoring is so loud I can't sleep.
— I see!
Is that so? Wait...
Man, he sure tosses a lot in his sleep!
I won't be able to get...
a good night's sleep!
Wait, Naruto! Wake up!
That's going too far...
Good morning!
Huh? What's going on,
Captain Yamato?
Oh, just something...
But how could he sleep
through all that?
Hey!
What is it?
Kakashi-senpai, that's not fair.